So, Mama, as someone who's trying to
learn English, I can find that British
time expressions can be quite confusing.
>> Oh, really? Which ones?
>> Like, people say half seven, and I don't
know if that means 6:30 or 7:30.
>> Well, that one means 7:30 cuz half seven
says half an hour after seven.
>> Oh, after. Okay, so quarter past would
be
>> A quarter of an hour, so 15 minutes past
seven, 7:15.
>> Okay. I also hear people say
"to." So, they say quarter to or 10 to.
What does that
>> Yeah. So, that means if you say quarter
to eight, that means a quarter of an
hour, so 15 minutes to eight, which
means 7:45.
>> So, you count backwards.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay. So, do lots of people and young
people still say that, or do they use
the numbers?
>> Nowadays, they're more likely to use the
numbers, I think. So, most people will
say 7:50 instead of 10 to 8. But, it's
still good to know it just in case you
need a boomer.
>> Okay. And everyone still understands it.
>> Everyone still understands it, of
course.
>> Okay, thank you. I understand now.
>> No worries. Not understanding your
friends in the UK or want to sound more
natural when speaking in conversation?
Equip yourself with all the cultural
knowledge that you need to feel great
while in the UK. Each week with our UK
culture courses, you'll get classes with
a local teacher online, homework with
videos of Suzy about culturally relevant
topics, and it's all super relevant to
your everyday life. We'll provide you
all the material you need to navigate
those awkward moments. Sign up at
suzymaru.com/culture.
Comment "culture" below for more info.